树木
Trees.
我通常会说
Normally, I would say.
我不知道在采访中我不知道我是否会问一些关于树木的问题
I don't know, in an interview, I don't
know if I'd ask something about trees
除非他们是一位很高级的工程师
unless they're a pretty senior engineer
cuz it's not something we think about.
下一个问题是我失败了
This next problem is one that,
I failed it.
我失败了，卡兹我从没想过树木。
I failed it hard,
cuz I never thought about trees.
但一旦我了解如何解决这个问题
But once I understood how
to solve the problem,
真的改变了我对树木工作方式的看法
really it changed my perspective
on the way trees work.
我喜欢好吧我明白了
I'm like, okay, I get it.
我可以用树来迭代
I get how to iterate through a tree.
但在我被迫去做，被迫失败之前，我什么都没学到。
But until I was forced to do it and
forced to fail, I didn't learn anything.
我就像，树木，我知道树木。
I was like, yeah, trees, I know trees.
DOM 是树凉爽
The DOM is a tree, cool.
我什么时候才能用这个
When am I have to use this?
但在我拿到这个问题并失败之前，我没有强迫自己去学习它。
But until I got this question and failed
it, I didn't force myself to learn it.
但一旦你学会了树木
But once you learn trees,
你所了解的知识是适用于任何树的。
you kind of, the knowledge you
learn is applicable to any tree.
卡兹树是你穿过树的方式一般都是一样的
Cuz trees are, the way you traverse a tree
is generally gonna be the same way.
有不同种类的树木，我绝对不会去。
There's different types of trees,
which I'm definitely not gonna go into.
我很肯定还有一个 Fronsend Master的课程
I pretty sure there's another
Frontend Master's course which talks more
有关树算法和不同类型的信息。
about tree algorithms and different types.
我们今天不会这么做的
We're not gonna do that today.
我们要做最基本的树
We're just gonna do the most basic tree.
但要从树上下来
But gonna start off with a tree.
如果你对树木一无所知
If you didn't know anything about trees,
我当时没有，所有的树都有两个属性。
which I didn't at the time,
all trees have two properties.
它们有根，树从那里开始，它们有节点。
They have a root, where the tree begins,
and they have nodes.
为了打破这些节点，孩子，有父母和
And to break up those nodes,
the child, there's are parents and
有孩子。
there are children.
当然，孩子们是父节点的子代。
The children, of course,
are the children of the parent node.
所以根，根底下的一切都是孩子。
So the root, everything
underneath the root is the child.
当然，根本身也是一个节点。
But of course the root
itself is a node as well.
你想以编程方式思考这个问题的方式是父母。
And the way you wanna think about
this programmatically is the parent.
如果你觉得我不知道父母孩子
If you thought, I don't know,
parent.children?
你如何代表孩子们在树上的位置 ?
How would you represent the position
of the children on a tree?
我知道，这有点棘手，但如果我们说这个是零和一个呢 ?
I know, it's a little tricky, but
what if we said this was zero and one?
如果我有三个孩子怎么办
What if I had three children?
应该是零一二
It'd be zero, one, two.
零，一，二，三，四。
Zero, one, two, three, four.
这就是如果你从左到右，我们就会跳树的顺序。
That's how we would jump the order of the
tree if you're reading from left to right,
一般都是这样想的
and that's generally
how you think about it.
以编程方式，我们会说，这是一个数组。
Programmatically, we'd say,
that's an array.
因此，从 JavaScript 对象的角度来看这一点。
So think of this in terms
of JavaScript objects.
Parent.子代是项的数组。
Parent.children is an array of items.
因此，索引 0 中的子代 1 将成为某个节点，它将成为该节点。
So child 1 at index 0 is gonna be
some node, it's gonna be this node.
子代 2 将是此节点，依此类推。
Child 2 is gonna be this node,
and so on and so forth.
这将适用于下一个问题。
This will be applicable for
this next question.
我们都知道和爱的树是什么
So what's a tree that we all know and
love?
我已经说过四次了
I've said it like four times already.
>> DOM。
&gt;&gt; DOM.
>> DOM，是，是树。
&gt;&gt; The DOM, yes, it's a tree.
DOM 有哪些属性?
And what does the DOM have for properties?
你有一个根，这是 HTML ，它总是以 HTML开头。
You have a root, that's HTML,
it's always gonna start with HTML.
那么你可能有一个身体，一个标题，一个头。
Then you have maybe a body,
a title, a head.
是一棵树，每棵树都有什么 ?
It's a tree, so what does every tree have?
给你个提示
Give you a hint.
子节点。
Child nodes.
你可能已经习惯了，我们可能在一个早期的例子中使用过这个。
And you've probably actually used that, we
might have used that in an early example.
.child 是如何将子节点获取到父节点。
.children is how to get
the child node to the parent.
因此，每个 HTML 元素都有一个子代，它具有您可以保证的父代。
So every HTML element has a children,
it has a parent you can guarantee that.
如果我想通过数组进行迭代。
If I wanna Iterate through an array.
所以，如果我点击一些东西，我想说，我点击了什么 ?
So if I click something and
I wanna say, what did I click on?
Cutz 事件不工作什么的
Cuz event's not working or something.
我只会说 .parent， .parent， .parent， .parent。
I would just say .parent,
.parent, .parent, .parent.
我只是在迭代
I'd just iterate up.
如果我想迭代下去我说处于零位的孩子
If I wanna iterate down,
I say that children at position zero,
点孩子们的反对声音我正穿过一棵树
dot children opposition one and
that way I'm moving through a tree.
我要给你公平的警告，这个是很有挑战性的。
I will give you fair warning,
this one is was challenging.
但我觉得这很有用，因为一旦你了解了这个方案，
But again, i think it's helpful because
once you understand the solution,
此问题，您了解如何迭代树。
this problem you understand
how to iterate through a tree.
如果你能理解唐你能理解的唐
Using Dom as a good exposure,
that if you understand Dom you understand,
i 可以迭代二进制搜索树，也可以迭代 vl 树。
i can iterate through a binary search
tree or I can iterate through a vl tree.
或许多不同类型的树。
Or many different types of trees.
所以，对于这个问题，我已经抽出来了。
So for this particular problem,
I have drawn it out.
你给了两个 DOM 树
You're given two DOM trees.
所以想想，我不知道，如果你想，我不知道两个不同的网页副本。
So think of, I don't know, two different
copies of webpage if you wanted to.
或者说你冒犯了你的 DOM
Or let's say you offloaded your DOM,
你的虚拟 DOM 变成了一个网站工作者你想做个迭代
your virtual DOM, into a web worker,
and you wanna iterate through,
你想操纵它们所以你可以直接用 HTML
you wanna manipulate them both So
you can use HTML directly on those.
但你知道，我们是一个元素不是树。
But you know,
we're one element isn't a tree.
你有一个 DOM 树
So you have a DOM tree.
它代表了一些只是 HTML的东西。
It's represents things that are just HTML.
假设你有一个一模一样的树
Let's say you have a clone
of that exact same tree.
您将如何获取给定元素的路径 ?
How would you get the path
to a given element?
所以如果我给你一个按钮一栋树的位置
So if I give you the location
of a button One domTree,
你怎么能在一个一模一样的圆顶里
how would you get to that
button in an identical domTree.
所以我会说更正式的方式是我们有两个相同的边界 A 和 B 。
So I'll say the more formal way we
have two identical boundaries A and B.
对于 DOM 树 A ，我们有位置和
For DOM tree A, we have location and
元素创意函数，用于在 DOM 树 B 中查找同一元素。
element creative function to find
that same element in DOM tree B.
这个我给你 20 分钟我一定帮你
For this one, I will give you 20 minutes
and I'll definitely help you out.
这个很棘手但想想我们已经知道的了
This one is tricky, but
think of what we know already.
我们对 DOM 树有什么了解
What do we know about DOM tree a?
我们知道它有根，很好。
We know that it has a root, fine.
但我们没有被赋予根
But we're not given the root.
我们被赋予了一个元素我们被赋予了另一棵树
We're given an element to find,
and we're given the other tree.
那么我们如何才能到达根，给出一个元素，任何一个节点?
So how would we get to the root,
given an element, any node?
所以，在这个节点上，我们如何才能到达这里 ?
So given this node how
do we get up to here?
>> 父代的递归。
&gt;&gt; Recursion from the parents.
>> 正好，您可以使用递归。
&gt;&gt; Exactly, you can use recursion.
我只说一个循环再走过去
I would just say a loop and
just walk back over.
因为我们知道一个事实的这个节点有一个父母。
Because this node we know for
a fact has a parent.
然后，此节点具有父节点，并且此节点具有父节点。
And then this node has a parent and
this node has a parent.
所以你可以每次都给家长打电话
So you can walk back up the tree
just calling the parent every time.
我再给你五分钟的提示
I'll give you another hint in
another five minutes or so,
但这应该让你走上正确的道路
but that should start
you on the right path.
好吧好吧
All right.
对，中间有个问题提示，因为这个是一个 " 挑战者" ，
Right, mid problem hint since
this one is a Challenging,
尤其是当你从未想到过树木的情况下
especially if you never
thought about trees.
但让我们想想我们知道的事情。
But let's think about the things we know.
我们知道我们可能需要某种功能
We know we're probably gonna
need some sort of function.
这将会有一些元素，然后它会把那棵树也带走，好吧。
And that's gonna take an elements and then
it's gonna take that other tree, okay.
但最终我们要做什么呢 ?
But ultimately what are we trying to do?
如果我说的话你会喜欢的我们正在努力去做树
And if I say it, you'll be like,
We're trying to go up the tree.
我们有这个元素，然后我们有另一棵树。
We have this element and
then we have this other tree.
这就是我们知道的
That's what we know.
我们正试图到这里来
We're trying to get to here, essentially.
然后，我们可以重放这条路径来到达这里。
And then, we can replay that
same path to get to here.
这将是反向路径算法。
So that would be a reverse path algorithm.
所以，你从这里开始，我们怎么走树呢 ?
So essentially you start here,
how would we walk up the tree?
我们会打电话给家长
We would call dot parent.
然后我们打电话给父母然后给父母打电话
And then we call the parent and
then we call the parent.
如果没有父母，我们就在根。
If there is no parent, we're at the root.
所以如果我们能把它储存在这里
So if we can store that.
然后我们可以回放它，让它后退到这里的树。
We can then replay that, reversing it
to walk back down the tree to here.
请记住，每个元素都有父代，并且有子代。
Remember that every element has
a parent and it has children.
这就是我给你的提示
That's the hint I'll give you.
所以我说，你想在你点击根节点之前迭代起来。
So I'll say, you want to iterate
up until you hit the root node.
然后你就想跳回去回去
And then you want to jump back,
go back down.